# Konstantinos Patlatzoglou, Ph.D.

♣ Thessaloniki, 54352, Greece

**4** 26/02/1992

+30 6945940517

konspatl@gmail.com

konspatl.github.io

in linkedin.com/in/konspatl/

github.com/konspatl

ORCID:0000-0002-5888-8490

#### **About**

Computer scientist, interested in AI, neuroscience and biomedical engineering. My research experience has mainly focused on areas of neuroinformatics within the domains of music cognition and general anesthesia. Currently, I'd like to explore and develop machine learning methods for scientific discovery and clinical applications.

### **Experience**

2017 - 2022

**■** University of Kent - Machine Learning Researcher

Researched and developed deep learning-based EEG models for automated, end-to-end, real-time monitoring of the depth of anesthesia.

**Skills:** • Python (*Tensorflow*) • EEG Analysis (*MNE*) • Digital Signal Processing

• NeuroInformatics • Machine Learning/Deep Learning • Research Methods

2017 - 2021

University of Kent - Teaching Assistant

Preparation, teaching, and marking of undergraduate modules in Computer Science.

#### **Education**

2017 – 2022 **Ph.D. in Computer Science** - University of Kent

Thesis title: Deep Learning for Electrophysiological Investigation and Estimation of Anesthetic-Induced Unconsciousness.

Anesinetic-Induced Unconsciousness

2015 – 2016 M.Sc. in Sound and Music Computing - Universitat Pompeu Fabra

Grade: 8.53/10

Thesis title: Neural and Music Correlates of Music-Evoked Emotions.

2010 – 2015 **B.Sc. in Informatics** - Aristotle University of Thessaloniki

Grade: 8.69/10 (First Class Honours)

Thesis title: A study of causal interactions during music listening based on EEG signals using estimates of nonlinear correlations.

#### **Skills**

**Languages** Greek (*Native*), English (*Proficiency*)

**Coding** Python, Java, Matlab, C

**ML Libraries** Scikit-learn, Tensorflow, Keras

Misc. MS Office, LATEX, Unix Shell, Git, Slurm

### **Activities and Interests**

- Biomedical EngineeringEvolutionary Biology
- Cognitive Science and Psychology
- Massive Open Online Courses (MOOCs)
- Music Perception and Cognition
- Music Composition and Production

### **Teaching**

2017 - 2021	Introduction to Object-Oriented Programming
2017 - 2019	Advanced Object-Oriented Programming
2019 – 2021	Data Structures and Algorithms
2019 – 2020	Agile Development and Software Security
2018 – 2020	Computing Theory and Concurrent Programming

## **Research Publications**

- Patlatzoglou, K. (2022). Deep learning for electrophysiological investigation and estimation of anesthetic-induced unconsciousness (Doctoral dissertation, University of Kent,). Retrieved from https://kar.kent.ac.uk/97272/
- Patlatzoglou, K., Chennu, S., Gosseries, O., Bonhomme, V., Wolff, A., & Laureys, S. (2020). Generalized Prediction of Unconsciousness during Propofol Anesthesia using 3D Convolutional Neural Networks. In 2020 42nd annual international conference of the ieee engineering in medicine & biology society (embc) (Vol. 2020-July, pp. 134–137). Odoi:10.1109/EMBC44109.2020.9175324
- Patlatzoglou, K., Chennu, S., Boly, M., Noirhomme, Q., Bonhomme, V., Brichant, J.-F., ... Laureys, S. (2018). Deep Neural Networks for Automatic Classification of Anesthetic-Induced Unconsciousness. In Lecture notes in computer science (including subseries lecture notes in artificial intelligence and lecture notes in bioinformatics) (Vol. 11309 LNAI, pp. 216–225). doi:10.1007/978-3-030-05587-5\_21

# **Conferences and Workshops**

Sep 2020 Jul 2020	R	Pattern Recognition in Neuroimaging (PRNI) Summer School, Vienna, Austria 42 <sup>nd</sup> Annual International Conference of the IEEE Engineering in Medicine and Biology Society (EMBC), Montreal, Canada Invited Talk: Generalized Prediction of Unconsciousness during Propofol Anesthesia using 3D Convolutional Neural Networks
May 2020		Brain, Cognition, Emotion and Music (BCEM) Conference, Kent, UK
Nov 2019		Studying Consciousness in the Electrical Brain - Luminous Workshop, Oxford, UK <b>Poster Presentation:</b> Classification and Regression Analysis of Anesthetic States using Electroencephalography and Deep Learning
Jul 2019		3 <sup>rd</sup> International Summer School on Deep Learning, Warshaw, Poland
Jun 2019		${\bf 1}^{\rm st}$ Interdisciplinary Research on Brain Network Dynamics (Brandy) Summer School, Terzolas, Italy
Dec 2018		11 <sup>th</sup> International Conference on Brain Informatics, Arlington, Texas  Invited Talk: Deep Neural Networks for Automatic Classification of Anesthetic-Induced Unconsciousness

# **Conferences and Workshops (continued)**

Sep 2018 Complex Systems Society (CCS) Conference, Thessaloniki, Greece
Invited Talk: Classification Analysis of Levels of Consciousness under Anesthesia, using Electroencephalography and Deep Learning Techniques

Sep 2017 International Symposium on Performance Science (ISPS), Reykjavik, Iceland **Poster Presentation:** Neural and Music Correlates of Music-Evoked Emotions